k
[Music]
[Applause]
come
oh
[Music]
[Music] [
Applause]
[Music]
life What a journey it is so and so
diverse and now more than ever so
unpredictable
aidc of moments moment shaped by the
decisions we make and all of us make
thousands every single day these
decisions can be comp from how we choose
to invest to for later Life To Reaching
our greatest
goals we make these decisions easier
Every every
this drives what  we do from sharing
investment insights that Others may not
see to helping her make his education is
covered from rewarding him for staying
healthy to giving her the confidence to
S every day better is doing a job that
improves people's lives and Believing
that tomorrow will be better than today
[Music]
[Applause]
keep strong and importantly to keep
smiling for everyone Together let's keep
making every day
[Music]
better ready
lif you need a health plan that fits you
better get manual health
flex choose from four he  bundles to get
coverage for cancer heart attack stroke
and over 100 other critical
illnesses so you can start to make every
day
better find healthy that fits you
perfectly ask your insurance advisor
about
it
lif you need a health plan that fits you
better get manual life heal
FX choose from health bundles to get
coverage for cancer heart attack stroke
and over 100 other critical
illnesses so you can start to make every
day
better find healthy that fits you
perfectly ask your insurance advisor
about
it
lif you need  a health plan that fits you
better get manual life
healx choose from he bundles to get
coverage for cancer heart attack stroke
and over 100 other critical
illnesses so you can start to make every
day
better find healthy that fits you
perfectly ask your insurance advisor
about
it
lif you need a health plan that fits you
better get manual
Hex choose from four health bundles to
get coverage for cancer heart attack
stroke and over 100 other critical
illnesses so you can start to make every
day
better find healthy that  fits you
perfectly ask your insurance advisor
about  it ready
lif you need a health plan that fits you
better get manual life heal
flex choose from four health bundles to
get coverage for cancer heart attack
stroke and over 100 other critical
[Music]
illnesses so you can start to make every
day
better find healthy that fits you
perfectly ask your insurance advice
about
it
lif and we are live a plus afternoon to
everyone I am luis manzano and let me
give you a warm Welcome to this
afternoon's wellness webinar This is the
fourth in a series of wellness webinars
brought to you by manual life
Philippines the question How are
you on our seventh month of quarantine
Yes it has been that long but we
continue to hope and pray for better
days to come aw putay lahat we're facing
very tough times that Might Be taking
its To both physically and mentally so
The question is how do we cope how do we
how do we take care of our health and
Our loved ones health well today our wellness
webinar will dive into that topic
This is flex your future personalize
your Journey to  health and
wellness now today we have guest
speakers who I am  very excited to listen
to as they share their health and
fitness journeys um to be perfectly
honest okay because I believe you
deserve my honesty um I was not supposed
to be a host today I should be a guest
speaker because if
we're talking about fitness, that's my Wang kata my
body but Alden ah sent me a text
he said Brother Luis ah maybe How about just being a
guest I said Alden
you're a good kid but he said Don't be
Alden first He said brother Luis can't be
at a ph5 I agreed so
I'm a host ph5 is hard now um so
Alden we'll be together soon
okay now kidding aside I'm very very
positive that what we hear from our
guests will help or inspire you to jump
Start your health and wellness habits
and of course make your everyday Better
now before we start may Ask our special
guests to please say Hi to everyone
watching Hello Hello everyone Hi guys Hi
how how
I heard everything you said
Ay
sorry
favorite Yes I did take a
guesting to you this is for you eh What are you
Al Nam what are you host comedian I
What are you Oh my
after that
we see them Later on and we have
close to 5,000 attendees today wow now
throughout the program I will ask our
speakers a lot of questions and this is
my advice to you grab this
chance to ask them to if you have
questions all you have to do is ask away
in our q&a box at the bottom right side
of your screen and Later on our guests
will address these questions in our q&a
Session okay aside from the valuable
insights We will get from today's topic
now we  have raffle winners from our
viewers this afternoon now manual life
Philippines is giving away gift
certificates worth Php5,000
each to two lucky winners so guys stay
tuned until the end of the program if not
Alright You know I'm a slingshot of
raffles like that but I want you
guys to win it but I don't want to keep
you waiting so Actually we have a
lot to cover this afternoon so let's get
right to it now folks more than ever it
is very important that we  understand how
to keep ourselves healthy physically  and
mentally during the pandemic and while
in quarantine now did you know that
according to a recent health study
understanding Filipino sentiments
towards health and critical illness
conducted by manual life the top three
critical illnesses feared most by
Filipinos are cancer heart disease and
stroke so it's important to be aware of
how we can prepare and protect ourselves
and our family from critical
illnesses so today we have an expert to
Enlighten us more how to manage our
wellbeing as we go through all  sorts of
Emotions and how to remain physically of
course healthy amid this pandemic she
will give insights on critical illnesses
like cancer being a breast cancer
survivor and advocate herself now she
specializes in occupational medicine and
currently serves as the Philippine
leader for live strong foundation
friends Please join me in welcoming d J
Hi
Dora Hi
lis Please do the hon super happy to be
here be
here Mr please go
ahead Okay So um Good afternoon to
everyone Uh this afternoon's topic is
something really close to my  heart and
it's all about breast cancer and Mental
Health
awareness so on the next
slide Uh That's me in a nutshell
why I'm narrating this It's because it
has affected me in a lot of ways Uh work
was my
life I am a doctor and my passion is
medicine but on the next
slide What happens when Uh I take
physically care of
patients But what happens when the role
gets reversed
so 8 years ago that was February
2013 and that's my picture um with no
hair
um I discovered a lump that made me wish
I was not a doctor after 42 Years of My
Life since I knew at that time
the
lump was ugly so just to give you a back story
on how it happened my Dad called me ah
sa so The duration of our conversation ah
my right hand was holding
my left breast and so ah when
my right hand was resting
on my
right um it felt like a
table so I said to Dad call I'll call
you back and then when I started to
palpate it it was very ugly So it had
all the
characteristics of Cancer  of Cancer so
next slide next
SL and so breast cancer and the  Mental
Health um they cannot be
separated because come to think of it
when we define health It's physical
mental and social so next
slide So this is based on who else in
2018 showing that breast cancer
tops the L among other cancers as
well next
slide Okay next slide
please and this is based from the global
cancer Observatory so Uh breast cancer
still tops the top five most frequent
cancers excluding skin cancer next
side so these are the key preventions still
no so keep a healthy weight exercise
regularly limit the alcohol  intake
consult your doctor and for
breastfeeding women breastfeed if
possible so we still do the five
pillars of prevention next slide
and um This is the
mammogram the recommendation is by 40
years old above um we undergo this and
so this is what I missed I kept
preaching before about um health but
unknowingly I neglected myself
and so whenever I get asked ah what is
my biggest regret in my life It's
not really Uh walking the talk so next
slide and Here are some tips on how to
perform a routine self breast
exam so number one  ah we need to
look at ourselves in the mirror because
one possible Uh sign of breast cancer is
uneven
how do bre Look
froms and then number
two self breast
examination and for women we advise it to be
done after
menstruation and then number three
she should do both ways Ah so standing up and
lying down because some lumps you won't
feel that when standing up so
she should posture next
slide and so we understand no the
psychosocial
struggles of um individuals Living with
cancer and so the factor
of
uncertainty is always there up to now whenever  if you
were to ask me the
fear
um of having fear of recur
na
balikari and then there of loss of
function So all
that we take that into
consideration in terms of psychosocial
issues with even cancer survivors as
well next
slide then These are the
statistics of both mental health and
cancer to 24% higher risk for
depression and three times the rate of
major depressive disorders
so next
slide and distress is Actually the sixth
vital sign in cancer care so when we
explain the stress it's  multifactorial
it's unpleasant um And  it can interfere
with the way we C
effectively So why do we need to
talk about it Uh it can lead to negative
consequences for the patient and family
and poor Health
outcomes next
slide and so the cancer patient is in
the
middle when we talk about their needs
and Mental Health support social work
social work counseling C and of course
Uh Chaplin services in
Whatever Faith you believe in next
slide and these are Actually the top Uh
six
concerns in Uh cancer patients there
changes in family and
relationships sexual life is
considered and having kids  fertility is
an issue especially when child bearing
years returning to work or finding a job
a job managing
finances and finding new hobbies and
interest as well next slide ah doora
Gia Yes lu Yes I apologize for
interrupting your presentation May I ask
for a small
favor sure Uh May we ask you please mute
your Zoom device device
Okay I turned him
off the
presentation Alright Luis mag ano te issues
to go on Okay no problem So you're G to
wa for presentation
no problem do Yeah it's just that we
were  hearing an echo earlier yeah yeah
no problem  We'll get back to
you so we apologize for everyone as you
can see This is happening Uh Live na
live and of course it happens once in a
while you will have your technical
difficulties
So we're just waiting for doc Gia to get
ready with her presentation and Okay I
can present without Zoom Is that okay Uh
Yes Go ahead please
Okay um Let's take off from the support
slide Okay the support the cancer
patient in the
middle so the cancer patient is in the
middle Wala na ak zoom
that's the  14th slide basically if not
mistaken doc you were about to talk
about
Spirituality Yeah right So
um the next slide is Actually talking
about Spirituality so it's actually the
strongest predictor of social wellbeing
and it's a significant predictor also of
emotional and functional wellbeing in
the quality of life in terms of patients
and family as well so on the next slide
sorry for tech difficulties I really
apologize no wor St it happens so on the
next slide it states that Uh It's so
important that we are able to provide
hope no matter  how the shape of Hope
comes in so Reflection reevaluation
I also learned that sometimes
you
need Hope is really powerful in terms of
not only in caner but I think in all
aspects of our lives we really need
to be reassured that there is indeed hope
and of course in cancer there has to be
a balance of Truth telling and nurturing
hope at the same
time so on the next
slide is a slide Uh specific in terms of
dealing with individuals with Mental
Health challenges so the first um point
that  I'd like to make is that all
feelings are valid no everything
we feel both positive and
negative They're all valid and never
assume the capacity of a person
to be able to handle His
feelings or Emotions and that
demonstrating understanding and support
Uh is really important most especially
during this
time so on the next
slide is a picture of my family why am I
showing this because They are the ones who became
my curse of Hope um I Remember When I
was diagnosed my my kids asked me um
mommy Are you gna die so I said  to
them
um Mommy will fight for you and  So um
like reassurance that my family was
there that really mattered at that time
and even up Until Now When
I still really have uncertainties in terms of
How if it recurs
and so the last slide is something that
I realized and um on that picture
Actually what's wrong I showed my scar
on that
picture I no longer have a left breast and I
showed my scar because this is a
realization that I had is that life is
really a balance between what we can
control and what we can but at a point
in our lives  we have to learn to live
comfor
between effort and
Surrender so that ends my short
presentation for this afternoon um I'm
sorry for the technical difficulties but
um it happens so there Thank you Luis
back to you Thank you very much Dr Mommy
will fight for you wow that that's
Struck a I think every mom would do the
same
thing and thank you very much for being
very candid and open about your Journey
battling breast cancer and for such
wonderful insights on taking care of
your physical and mental wellbeing now
folks I'm sure you have a lot of
questions  for d Jia so please type in
the q&a box at the bottom of your screen
and Dr Jia will answer them Later on in
our q&a session now indeed looking after
our physical and Mental Health is vital
for us to come out Victorious in our
battle against this pandemic and
speaking of this battle against covid-19
Our next special guest is someone who
experienced the ordeal first hand she is
a multi-awarded winning actress an
advocate of empowering women
organization she co-founded she Talks
Asia body love and  Mental Health
awareness advocate and recently a
covid-19 Survivor wow without a doubt We
will get so much from this and I'm
excited to hear from her so I won't
delay any longer Please join me and
giving a warm Welcome to Miss ia
calsado Hi Luis Thank you so much for
that Lovely intro
um wow You deserve all the kindest words
and more
Thank you and so do you we all do I know
Hello to those who were watching we've been watching
before but Hello again I know it's
been a while since you know um you  had
covid-19 and you know I'm  glad to see
you healthy Thank you Luis I remember
you posting a picture you were in the
hospital then you had you know you were
Getting your oxygen and nice to see that
we're having this conversation under the
new normal and you being perfectly
healthy Thank you i i only have God to
thank but but also not only Of course
primarily I have God to thank but I have to
thank of course our frontliners my my
frontliners who took great care of me
during that time but really people who
prayed for me and I know you are one of them  Of
course you know everyone knows your
health buff is it much easier to be one
if your partner or your significant
other is also a health buff from you
know how you exercise to What you
eat um Yes ah thanks for asking that
question So we have a little ah
benal moment here ah yeah it really
helps if you and your partner are on the
same page there's Ben Ah so Ben has been
active all his life when we met Uh I
actually was the one who introduced him
to like paleo diet I was wow Yeah
I know he's the one with abs  guys but ah um so
because of of my history  I've you know
battled Uh the weight to keep the weight
off no for so many years and um It it
really helps to have somebody who
doesn't Just do it to look good But
rather he he does it because he wants to
be healthy Ah yes yes raise the shirt
Yes I combined looking good and
staying healthy Yes That's what Luis said
you stretched
Yes It's true oh yeah I know what
you are Healthy Living too so does
it really matter and and you and your
your Lovely partner your how cute
you guys really are Jess and I know you also
have a healthy lifestyle together so to
answer your question it really does make
a difference because it's like if
I have a partner I'm with you in the choices
that we make ah for ourselves and It's
really these choices are vital because
they are choices that we will be making
for our future family yes yes I mean
It's a It's a longterm commitment
exactly so since you subscribe to a
healthy diet you work out  How was it
when you got the news that you
Contracted covid-19
Yeah You know
you said not You're you're healthy you
know I heard doc Gia say earlier
she wasn't walking the talk Yes I I can
understand that and I'm guilty of it
because I'm supposedly healthy But there
are a few things that I was lacking in
um I know this wasn't your question Luis
but I have to say this Because I feel
like um whoever is watching this right
now this Might Be helpful um so what
you said  eat well true generally you
know I I do have my indulgences but i
generally Eat well um I work out which
can also be a problem because I work out
even when I'm very tired because of the
pressure of the industry Is there such a thing
So when we were
younger so but you still are I said
younger we still Are luise we still are
um We will be forever young
so and But you know one of the things
that I didn't have is um regular hours
of sleep because of the nature of our
work and  Honestly that is the one thing
that Ben And I  were different in in
terms of lifestyle with him,
he sleeps very regular hours I am erratic So if I
may just emphasize the value of getting
good sleep please whoever sw watching
this that is a vital um part of wellness
So that's all so to answer your question
when i found
out when I got sick you know I got sick
First I was actually in the house for
seven days thinking it was just a bad
Case Of The Flu which to me was not
surprising because in the past three
years I have been sickly again because
of the lifestyle and apparently I little
did I know that I I had like a
subclinical hypothyroidism already and
that my immune system has been very weak
the past couple of years so always I was
actually sick my bachelorette sick
during my wedding and I was just sick
during Christmas all flu Yeah I've been
maybe I would get the flu I would be
down for about three four times a year
mga ganon That's a lot for the flu
that's that's a lot and like really
it will take 2 weeks for me to
bounce back Ah so I when when I was  sick
during this time this was the beginning
of the pandemic especially in the
Philippines we had just Lockdown I was
thinking Wow this is just a flu But you
know it was getting worse by the day
until such time that I was taken to the
hospital and told I had
pneumonia How did it feel it was like a
huge wakeup call I was poured like
cold water was poured on me Luis
like Oh my god pneumonia t's the
doctor in the er all signs are pointing
covid of course We will test you We
can't um We can't know For sure until
after seve  ral days because you know at
the time the rhythm is still the Ah there is
only one more Yes the one with pcr so but they started
treating me as if I were a covid patient
and it really made me realize a lot of
things health is really the most
important thing that we have in our life
and I am
healthy but it made me question
A lot of um the decisions that i made
for myself and how I was living my life
Well I said it before and I'm going to
say it again when everything has been
said and done I'm glad to  see that
you're healthy and your family is as
well but the question is how are you
post covid Did you have changes in your
lifestyle or you know something as
Simple as you going out or is it still
the same routine same habit yeah Well of
course We don't go out all of us Don't
go out as often as we used to no ' ba
and plus I I'm very Grateful we were one
of the first to do taping in this Uh new
normal setup so by July I was taping na
so we would  quarantine a lot so I don't
have a lot of  time really to go out
having said that I've been more mindful
of course of washing My Hands the
alcohol you know I realized also how
touchy I am on my face I actually
Contracted a bacterial infection when I
was in the hospital so I had a viral
infection in my lung which was covid and
then I got a bacterial infection which
is called acinetobacter baani which is
apparently very hard to treat and it was
so I was battling two things in my lungs
and that is normally
Uh hospital  born What is that called
doc G which Was You Contracted and you
get it from the hospital so I realized
Mama you know I touch my face so much so
these are one of the things that I have to
really be conscious of now like
Once I touch a surface Be careful
touching your face so I guess the mask
the ey shield It It it really is some
kind of protection that we have in terms
of lifestyle we have different protocols
now when it comes to taping so I'm glad
that we end taping at around  800 pm
every time Is You know difficult  he
because of the different kind of setup
but at least we get some kind of
regularity in terms of our sleep um and
I would really like to keep It That Way
I feel like my wife won't let me have
all nighters
anymore because she really doesn't. Like
Luis you can really tell I said this
in the hospital what all this is for if if if
my health is not at its best you know if
I'm going to you know I'll be Frank you
know I I did have to face that like
if I was dying what all
my work is for is staying up that
simple eh So um those are the things
that changed for me the way I value that
and also the way I value what I choose
to spend my time on and who I choose to
spend my time on and thank you for
spending this afternoon with us Yeah of
k para sayo lang talaga h para siempre
you know I I was Given an opportunity
Thank you manu life um always as an
opportunity to share what I've learned
ah but is it with that being said do you
have any message for you people
right now battling the
virus Yeah you know  um It's very tough
to be in that position and there are
it's not just a physical struggle like what was
said earlier by doc G as a breast
cancer um Survivor no and when she was
going through It anybody who experiences
any kind of challenge it's not just a
physical like a you know if you're
facing chronic disease is what we talked
about a while ago like any kind of illness
it is beyond physical it is really a
mental challenge as well so there is a lot of
fighting so I guess my first
um message is
Keep the faith as doc G said earlier
Spirituality um is is very vital She
said that it's the most important aspect
of wellbeing and I would have to agree
with that no and um for anybody Who's
there right now
ah Just keep praying keep hoping um and
strengthen your immunity I I actually
know a lot of of people who didn't even
have symptoms but they said that the
mental battle was really hard for them
so if you are one of those um Just you
know Keep Keep praying and and  know you
have purpose purpose is so important  doesn't
that give you something to live for
um and there is also
um
Uh you know Luis covid has as much stigma
so a lot of people are afraid
to even talk about it and that's fine as
my doctor said your data is yours but
let's also be morally morally
responsible for those that we may have
come into close contact with not that
you minute that you feel something covid
or not I think it is your responsibility
to tell that person or those people and
definitely should you test Uh positive
so hopefully Hindi po ah
ah Please  reach out to people you need
not post about it on Social Media but Of
course you know by telling people there
is that chance that people will find out
but I think it's really necessary to choose
between um your responsibility towards
others and the the shame and and I guess
my message also to the people to
everyone else is let's be compassionate
towards one another because we don't
know what each one is going through
so I hope there's no covid shaming so y
yes and I'll just go back maybe I one big
stress factor when it comes to covid  is
you know there are some who are
asymptomatic but I guess  one of the
biggest stress factors would be passing
it on to someone you
love No there are some people who are okay it's
okay that I got hit by covid It's
okay if i you know get confined if
I'm in the icu to pass it on to someone
dear to you sometimes that takes an even
bigger toll on your mental health
Ah You said it luis I think ah when
I was still sick before I was
hospitalized especially when I was in the hospital
I kept thinking about the people who
were near and dear to me or the people
that  I was Exposed to
um at that time I know a bit this maybe
sound privileged and I Yes I'm very
lucky that at that time they allowed
them to stay with me in the hospital ah
I mean I don't hide this because That's
a fact and I don't want to lie about it
um you know the doctors would look at
him everyday we even asked for tests
they said but He's healthy so you know
we don't really have test kits but we are
panicking his mother Of course  Is it like
he can't get tested What if  he has it
what you know super Ben stayed super Ben
the entire time and
um again So I'm going back to regular
hours of sleep so because I really don't
know what the difference was and um
surprise surprise when we would take the
antibodies antibody tests he has Uh some
antibodies so perhaps he got it Yeah
it's just that he was just his immune
system was strong so Again the emphasis
on having a strong immune system and
That's why I talked about being
responsible the minute you feel
something the best way really is  to
quarantine yourself um of course sorry if
they say you didn't do that
eh Sorry ha but because at that time
everything was new knowing what we know
Now I would say that This is the best
practice ah as a matter of fact can if I
may share in our taping any type of
flu likee symptom whether
the person needs to be negative
Uh this is how strict the protocols are
and it's hard but I think it is just
best practice for us to adhere to these
rules I completely agree now one more
thing  that's really close to your heart
is your advocacy  for Mental Health how
did that
start well lis
um the advocacy happened a little later
in life but um the awareness regarding
Mental Health I was basically born into
it because my mother
Uh had mental health issues Ever Since I
could remember from different
Uh manifest parang diagnosis Through The
Years until finally the correct one was
made I think I was in early high school
she was um bipolar Uh was was diagnosed
and I a year ago I came out finally with
with a story that I had lost my
mom 19 years ago  to depression
and it was it was tough to share that
but I felt it was time and I also
realized that all the things that I had
been advocating for previously such as
body love body acceptance All the Things
I was personally going through as well
it's all a mental self concern because
at the core of it is self love and
um so It just came hand in hand and so
that's really how it started And that's
why it's it's close to my heart because
it's a very personal
issue Well do you have any  message for
people who think who feel that they're
at the lowest point right
now
w those who feel that they are at their
lowest point
doc Jia said Hope is so
important
um I think when you're at your lowest
point It's so hard to see this How do
you cling on to hope What is Hope It's
such a
vague idea or concept but I think there
are ways there are tools that we can
Uh arm ourselves with such as doing
perhaps meditation practicing
mindfulness doing journal staying
connected
um and purpose I I go back to purpose
because that  gives you something to live
for no matter how difficult your life
may be and In Line with that I know this
is more on a self love Uh angle I just
said I was thinking about this um I
perhaps I may emphasize on life l
e no how difficult the challenges are in
your
life Learn from it so that's L learn
because it's it's all
L um It's a learning tool for your
growth ba um You have to at some point
realize that you can turn that struggle
into your strength G I  took that from
Mark Hen from our
webinar um I  the value of
interconnectedness value each and every
connection that you have f is
forgiveness ah I think we have to be
able to forgive ourselves and all those
people that may have done some wrong
things to us you know when you say say
self Love It's a matter of not feeling
enough because which is perhaps Might Be a
programming that we receive from the age
of 1 to 7 years old with people the
adults around us not even thinking and
not not not not consciously doing this to us
so we have to forgive them as well we
have to forgive them um and that that is
I guess the kindness and compassion
towards one another is rooted also on
that and e Enjoy enjoy life We only have
one life love it value It live it
mindfully of course and enjoy it well aa
Thank you very much for continuously
rallying behind the importance of mental
health and sharing so much about this
advocacy now with your powerful voice
you truly are such an inspiration to a
lot of people especially women about
selfcare I'll see you later on  on our
q&a session so let me Remind everyone if
you have questions oria and Miss EA you
can share them your thoughts in the q&a
box at the bottom right side of your
screen We'll get to that Later on
towards the end of the webinar well All
right one of my takeaways From This
webinar is so far is healthy lifestyle
promotes your overall health condition
it improves not just your physical
health but also your mental health and
overall wellbeing k naman interesting to
note that during this time of quarantine
or isolation a lot of people are being
very mindful of selfcare, pay attention to
that social media feed, there are a lot of
fitness enthusiasts, isn't it
like every time you scroll you will see
someone working out sharing a workout
progress and everything it goes to show
that people are trying to stay fit
amidst the pandemic and turn to online
workouts or virtual training and they
really find ways to be more healthy now
when it comes to improving overall
health and being the best version of
oneself, this
Great to Ong, our next special guest
she is  truly a fitspiration and I am
really thrilled  I'll be with her in
fact this will be the first time
I'll interview her no
I'm still crying someone I have seen at I
guess safe to say one of her lowest
points and hopefully at this point It's
a high point for her buse she has
this little face in her life and she
will share her fitness journey and well
Okay let's put it this way I'm so in
love I'm in love with our next guest
now we have the Star of the new show
fit for life none other than my Senorita
my ha my wowow Miss Jess I cried a
lot gra Hi how how Hello everyone
Thank you Thank you life for having me
today Your intro kiss
first is really great Okay like what I said
earlier how na you know I've seen your
your fitness journey and I was already
with you when you said you said that
There was a time that you weren't too
confident with you know how you were So
how was your fitness
journey Great Where do i start um It's
Been an up battle there were times na I
thought I was about  to give up But
of course I want to see How far I
could go and Alam mo Ian love as in
You saw my fitness Journey
you saw me even at my heaviest
and it's very important for me to
inspire others and Y nga tualong ng sabi
ni I kaninai and ni dochi um It's very
important to walk the talk um my whole
life bas
Akala ko healthy ako I thought it was
quite a bit of pressure to be the host of
a show that's titled I fit for life
but um It's very important of course to
spread awareness that being healthy also
comes from within hindi siya yyung
bigla-biglang siyasya It's a very
very long journey But you know it's
worth it and for me when you get to take
care of yourself When you get to take
care of your health and of course The
Other aspects in your life importante
yun kasi holistic approach yun eh more
of like you know you Take care of
yourself spiritually mentally and that's
your physical health So that's
uphill battle But you know I can assure
you to everyone listening or watching right
now it's all worth it and how how
I mean kumbaga kasi You Went both  sides
and there was a time What were your
struggles was it you gaining a bit of
weight bu There was a time naman naman na
according to you kwento mo na saakin and
I saw the pictures you were getting too
thin naman yes extremities really as in as in
extremes my transformation
from you know my my heaviest and then my
thinnest what is he um That's what
I always say in every
interview I do about health and about
fitness It's important to find that
balance in between um I I've experienced
everything um my many
insecurities up until now of course that
won't go away and
um that um It's very challenging to to
find out or to settle where you are
really happiest and Where you really
feel more relaxed and healthy
so you said earlier extremes Iyung
ginawa mo you were really thin tapos you
weren't comfortable with the weight that
you gained so what did it take for you
to achieve the body that you have
now
um I had to Roll with the punches as in
like I had to to to try Everything I had to
experiment with you know  with different
types of workouts um I had to to to
to learn how to be balanced
when it comes to food because I've
experienced um bed That's um Bench
eating disorder I had anorexia and
bulimia before i I experience all of
those and
um It's really hard to be happy with
yourself when you've experienced those
things of course like
EA said 'is it um pressure in
our industry um we need to always tip
to shape But you know um I
think for me It's I made
Sure I acknowledged my battle um I was
able to recognize it and then I I just
really had to do something about it and
I did and I'm still you know I'm still
pursuing my happiest disposition in life
and I think I'm on my way there or in
fact I am there right now and one battle
you went through And I was a you know
Witness to it first hand is the battle
with negativity battle with bashers So
how did you overcome all that to be you
know content somehow and now a
body positive
advocate how ba um of course  just
like I said earlier it has to  be a
holistic system um not just one person
it's not you know it's not about um
Mental Health lang It's not about you
know pleasing others to me
um You have to have a strong support
system and of course I can't
say I'm not
affected but of course
we're all just people we're still affected and
Especially at that time um I
remember I've had My Fair share of
experiences with bashing and being
called names you know but I had to I had
to keep going on I had to spread a
message that the only way to be truly
happy and healthy is to really accept
yourself your body type and you know You
shouldn't really stop there maybe That's
why I became a body positive positivity
advocate It's really hard that's what
you're not You're not walking the
talk It's really hard that's of course I
can't say I'm happy with my body
if I can't accept my body I
mean I'm a bit you know round here and
there But it's okay
we can't be alone  of looks everything is not
possible anymore
I mean you have to learn to accept
what you have but also you have to work
towards you know being the best version
of yourself not of anyone else Nice Nam
I'm just drinking water a lot Wait
just maybe you don't want to thank
your coach I'm doing your workout it's
amazing that it's free because because of the
workout I'm giving you you can
run from Manila to Pagodas I'm tired to
all those who don't know Of course to
those watching now Luis really what is he
he is very focused when it comes to
my workouts when it comes to my form
he watches over and um in fairness
he's a very good trainer so Guys what is
his fee Um it's just cheap gust
if you don't ask if you don't
ask how much Jesse and I are
last week we swam from Manila
to Katiklan we were that
strong how many hours I got it in about 28
minutes there were still some fish of
sum they were wild they couldn't get home I
swim that fast
how what are five tips that you can give
on for people that on how to stay fit
and glowing could be beauty could be
fitness  could be for their Mental Health
um Maybe you know for me That's Uh like
what I did I
accepted I accepted my body type um I
acknowledged the problem and I did
something about it um of course
physically you should always
always wear What feels comfortable
What's flattering according to your body
type and you know being comfortable with
what you are wearing will also make you
feel and look confident so Of course I said
I've had That's what I said um
I've had TV guess things I had you know
Uh stints that need to be pretty sexy yyung
damit may mga na naman na hindi ako masaya non may mga na na na
comfortable So that's where I learned that um
I've learned that lesson You have to be comfortable of what you
wear You have to
be comfortable in your movement in
your appearance so you don't think about it And so also
you know it shows eh it shows when you're
comfortable with what you are
wearing another is you know It's okay to
be insecure we all have insecurities
um Even if you're the most beautiful person on the face of the
earth You have insecurities
love but the most important thing
is to acknowledge accept and do
something about it Isn't it IT may not be
you know totally that
insecurity will be erased but at least you know
you're doing something about it and
that's What's important another thing is
you know it's not about looking good
physically it's not just like
I always say it's
holistic eh It's a holistic system and
it's not about you know looking good
physically It's also feeling good
about yourself um I started being
healthy when I changed my perspective in
life I used to be so I used to be such a
pessimist as in like everything
I see for myself that
I notice a lot and It's really hard
because of course when you're in this
kind of job or otherwise it's not  a
You are the number one critic of yourself
and that's hard because you are also the
number one fan of yourself. So you
have to be you have to be good. I mean
you have to feel good yourself and you
know it comes from the inside. I noticed
when the moment I started being positive
about myself about my perspective and
life it became like a plus when
I lost weight the one thing I don't
want to lift
my own bench but do others say
Wow You're so blooming you look good
and  You're such an inspiration and you
know that's basically what I want In My
Life To Be inspired
and you know to share my experiences
with others so I think it's more important
that you start with yourself inside and
then that's the moment that gradually
comes out from your aura from the
way you you you treat others from the
way you think so Yeah if if it's not if
something is robbing you from your inner
peace you Might as well Just let go of
itse it's not worth it Thank you very
much  How and I'm very very proud of your
Journey thank you  you Thank you my love di
ba qu muna isa pa isa baby
b well folks I hope you're taking notes
and personalizing your Journey to
fitness and like what Jessie mentioned
find the right workout for your body
after all because fitness isn't a one size
fits ba so don't forget to hit the q&a
box at the bottom right side of your
screen if you have questions for how how
and We'll get to that Later on et na
laban to et laban next extraordinary okay
now from one fitspiration to another we
are down to our last special guest he is
one of today's sought after stars most
sought after stars in the Philippines
and Whose fitness transformation is
without a doubt remarkable so I'm not clear
I'm not going to interview
myself okay we have something we'll
call But this is a lot many
changes happened in his life and
I'm excited For Our next special guest Do
you know now these challenging times
certain put our wellbeing to a test
So here to share his Journey on how he
dealt with anxiety and stress and
managing his businesses  amidst the
pandemic and of course Talks  about his
fitness Journey the Star of the highest
grossing film of all time and he was
awarded the prestigious Guillermo
Mendoza film actor of the Year and the
phenomenal box office star for 2020 h
I will be surprised if next year
he has a lifetime Achievement award Please
give a warm Welcome to Alden
Richards the whole time I didn't
do anything but laugh listening to the
interviews earlier Luis
Thank you very much
Alden is here Maybe you want to greet
all those who are watching us
That's to everyone Who's watching Hello
just because I see it on
Zoom it seems like the video is frozen is it still
frozen is it still frozen
Yes the content
of the video is frozen alen but I hear you as we're
having you know a bit of a technical
difficulty Please give a second two
apologize two two two a ayan
ayan aan aan better better better so
than bro Thank you for that introduction
brother Luis because I saw the script
Nothing, he didn't
mention the ones that were Awards
but thank you Thank you Uh Uh It's
very nice to be here  especially I'd like
to thank man life for Uh inviting me to
you know share a bit of my Uh fitness
Journey as well I'm so honored to be in
the presence of of course these very
inspirational
Uh those who gave inspirational
Talks about fitness and
being What is it What are
our questions there Okay Okay ah new
before we get before we get to our
questions to Alden I
just want to ask all of you ah now in
man life is maybe turn down
the screen a little bit because based on past projects
Alden and I are together on a
screen the computer is broken that
much Yes so P maybe turn down
the brightness a little or not so
your memory will fill up quickly because
this is too much for you to
handle pinagsasasabi ko
Okay you're very very bless It's pretty
evident you know things
achievements things that you do On TV
all the time So the main question is for
someone as you know blessed As You Do
you still get stressed Do you still get
you know
anxious yes yes of course IT Can't Be
help Of course like Uh Everybody Else
We are just people regardless of the stature
that we're in or what position
we're in life because anxiety and
stress Uh is part of life kumbaga
ah the more that increases
in age all the more that increases The
challenges that come to us and the
things that we don't
expect especially like What's
happening now this covid itg pandemic
ah it's hard But you know with the
right mindset and attitude
we can get through that and Alden you're also
in the food industry Isn't it yes yes
yes So how was it um is in the most
affected by this pandemic and ' do you
see the whole industry it was you know
chaos So how was it for you in your
business Are you it was it one of the
triggers that gave you stress and
anxiety one of the yes of course Uh
sobrang naafakat Iyung food industry
and I recently did a documentary about
Uh how how covid-19 affected the food
industry in a GMA News TV Special
and I really feel for them when I was doing
it while I was doing the vo after
we  shot all the footages and the
materials for the docu
ah I just stopped but as I was
reading it I was becoming really
emotional because
ah those businesses that were up 20
years 15 years with a Snap of a finger
that nothing closed and the pain is
like being in the Uh food business
I know the hardships I know
the classes how to start
especially the
small businesses those who
started from scratch those who
just wanted to take a chance want to
last in the food business that has been so
affected it's so unfair and
it's so Unfair yet We can't do anything
about it that's the hard thing to do e It seems
like there's no choice it's no
choice no matter how much we
want to push on what
we started ah the situation really
calls for us to you know to go with the
Flow because if we push even further or
if I mean given the situation right
now if we push even further the things
that we know that we can't do
at the moment It Might
cause greater damage so Sad
but surviving we we  we the food business
is surviving it's just really hard
up to Maybe one factor No that um
maybe that really strikes a chord with
us is know a lot of people also in the
food industry it's not simply losing
profit It's having to let go of the
people who work for you exactly exactly
sobra And that's much Harder 'is
working with someone you said for
the past 10 years 15 years or someone
you know who's given you nothing but
loyalty but reality dictates that  you
would have to let that person or the
staff go Yes um Ah that's really one
of the major Uh fact actors that are
depressing about What's happening
right now but um we're on our side in
our restaurant we're very proud to say
that we didn't let go that alone among
our employees even when the
pandemic started
ah because it seems like the situation is Uh
really depressing as it is It's like
you're still going to give problems to the
people you can help So what
we did was we fix their schedule we do a
ah  r rotation of schedule varies
like this date  staff next
week is different just so we just have nothing to
let go because life is so hard
now and
Uh we know it for a fact that the
business is not making any
profit
ah my sister Gemma and I agreed that
we will survive as long as we can
because we are poor people and
we are the last ones in
this time so maybe we can
find a way to not let them
go so that
um In That Way we still helped
our people like what you've said
brother Luis who gave us nothing
but hard work and loyalty all
throughout the years of business and
that very simple action that
you did speaks highly of not just how
you are as a boss But how you are as a
person Great job say Alden thank you
Thank you Okay so How do you maintain
all that you are one of the busiest
people in the industry even before ' ba
from TV to movies tapos your own
personal life How do you Ian Do you still get
to see your family or how do you When you have a
free day What do you do Yeah well
basically it seems Everything is about
balance naman There was  a time before
the pandemic ah I Have To admit
I was a bit of a workaholic
I was a bit of a focus on the fact
that I need to earn I need to work hard Uh
you know for longevity for for income
but
Uh to me in a way it's not a
blessing The pandemic but the time
given to me during the pandemic was
Uh nothing but Reflection reflection of
all the Years that I've worked so hard
all the Years that I've Uh I've spent in
working without Thinking of the things
that I'm already leaving behind so it's like a
realization that there
life is about balance you learn how to
balance your time your your your
work the things that you do for yourself
the things that you do for others as
well so not all
work Go home to your family or
relax Yes yes I was there
I was there for 3 months and then I just
left behind I don't even
know that our guy is that big
He's still good at speaking English to
me now so things like that small
things like that for then Ah the yung
My grandparents saw me like
Wait, it seems like the size of
my grandparents' notes is that big, is that what
I missed out on since I've
been very busy so I have to say that it
was my fault it was my choice Actually
becoming a workaholic because
I wanted to Secure a Secure Uh the
future for my family for myself as well
but I didn't know that
my relationships with the people
that I love were so that's Uh That's on me
and it seems that's when I realized now that the
pandemic has taken time for
realization is
ah once everything comes back to normal
and slowly it's going back to normal
somehow ah learn how to balance
everything You can't just focus on one thing
regardless of what it
is right okay but It's my biggest
transformation that we saw with
Al when you didn't add recently we saw something
different your condition Alden is different So
how was that transformation because didn't
everyone used to say that Boy
Next Door has a little cheeks
That ad is just big. Yeah, it's hard, but
the fun story behind that was,
um, I started working out without even
the inquiry of that ad to get me as an
endorser. It was like when the
year started, I said to my team, let's get this
brand. Uh, let's get this
brand this year. Uh, I'll start working
out and work hard to achieve that kind
of body that's. Uh, that fits the
requirement of that ad. And then it's like, it's
true enough. Love and
attraction. When you think of it, when you
work hard for it, when you want that
thing to happen and to come into your
life, and you really work hard for it, it will
come. So that's like an
affirmation for me that
the law of attraction is true. When you want
something, you work hard for it, you pray
for it, and you be patient about it.
The picture is really great. Alden, give
me just 1 minute, just 1
minute, just hope that brand will renew
for me. I hope that brand will renew for me. I
hope that brand will renew for me.  I don't have
a brand, I hope I can renew my brand
okay, no inquiry yet, but hopefully by
this week, hopefully by this week, I hope
I can renew my brand okay, but then there are
so many people and I know this because
this is what happens to
our friends, they all want to work out, they all
want to start working out, but once you
start working out, the hardest part is to
continue that lifestyle, and
there are so many excuses, are the gyms so far away?
What will be the
best advice to people who want to start
working out to start a whole new them?
Yeah, that's really basic for everyone who
wants to start their
own fitness journey. You
have to start somewhere. I don't know
where it really depends on the
person.
You have to find the passion and
the drive for yourself. You want to
be healthy. You want to achieve this. Your
goal in your body and slowly. It's
not like you want to
improve your body. You have to lift
heavy weights or whatever. You have to diet. You have to
crash diet. That's right.
Sometimes the wrong connotation of being
healthy for other people is that they seem to want to be
fast and then the ending is
ah with the wrong results that come it can
end up into a sickness or a different
appearance etc so Everything is a slow
process when it comes to being healthy
Ah what you should really start
above as more please with working Out is
really eating healthy Iyung diet because
nowadays Uh based on the latest study
the I see and read online
it's an 8020 Uh mm process right now
It's 80% What you eat And 20% exercise
because it doesn't matter how hard you work out
at the gym or how hard you do your
exercises and yet you indulge on foods
that are not good or don't
worry about the result so
eating healthy and eating right is the
first step Uh in achieving the body that
you want you for you where are you embarrassed
to workout are you used to weights are
you used to body weight What did you find
for SAO
Ah for me because ah shoutout to
my coach kay coach If  You're watching
ah It
seems like she was looking for what
she was looking for ah in our first few sessions
she made me try a lot of workouts
and then Uh as we go along she saw
where I was and what I wanted to
do yet there are results great PR
good progress good programs as
well but Uh you especially to
everyone Who's watching
ah It's time to really get a personal
trainer you can really start start up by
looking online what
workouts you want because there are so many
workouts now that we can see
online
ah she's not the Typical
weightlifting there are so many different
programs online that
those who want to work out can try that they can enjoy
at the same time because That's I
think that's one of the key factors
in working out eh you look for a
workout that's fun yung yung yung mag-enjoy
ka that's doing meron na diyang zomba meron na diyang
ah mga body workouts and
ah There are so many options eh that's
ah the beauty of online and the beauty
of the internet we can see many things that
will fit us and  we can
choose ah we can choose from it for free
Actually there is no fee Yes that's right that's the
only thing ah It's like Ah one of the things
I can give them advice is take time
like in your free time you just since
everyone is online everyone is on
their phone it's easy there are many options you
can see Uh online
workouts and how to start of a healthy
lifestyle Uh with the with with fun
exercises said about the world and all
that information that Comes with it is
that your fingertips Yes Yes exactly
so much information because of
internet because of the internet Thank
you very much Al we see that
discipline really really is key in
living a healthier life now this will be
our driving force to push for and stick
with our fitness goals also What Struck
me with everything now is how you dealt
with stress and anxiety and of course
what you did for your employees that
deserves a round of applause good job
job remember we must always save
up always ready no one ever
anticipated whatever is happening
now but somehow being prepared
for something  unseen something like
this helps lighten the load  so thank you
very much Alden and I will see you later
on for our q&a thank you
so once again everyone it is not too
late to hit the q&a box and ask your
questions from our speakers if
you have a question for me go ask me
I will answer now right now Uh I See
all the questions we're getting a lot of
questions from our audience and I'm very
excited to Hear our guests answer all
those questions but please before that
make sure to stay tuned until the end of
our webinar manual because life is
giving away gift certificates worth
5,000 to two lucky winners so watch out
for that now before we proceed with the
audience q&a would like to first
acknowledge the presence of our friends
from the media we have Manila Bulletin
Manila Times Manila standard malaya
business insight daily tribune Sunstar
Cebu we have GMA Cosmo when in manila
click the city and We also have digital
Filipina lemon green tea and analin net
which brings us to the next part Hello hello once
again Hi
everyone All right
hello all
and we have a lot of great questions from
our viewers right  now so kayo for All
These
questions
ready doc Gia will be starting with
you and the question is my mom had a
mammo despite this the lump was Not
detected until She had a breast
ultrasound What is the difference
between a mammogram and a breast
ultrasound um technically Uh m should be
able to trace Uh really Even the small ones
but then again there also some C or mes
that the ultrasound can handle but in her case
the fib cystic small
lumps that are hormonal in nature most
likely are more detectable by ultrasound but
technically more  the mammogram is sensitive
Okay thank you very
much most practical tips for us gents to
be physically and mentally fit and
attract the girl of our dreams that's really bad
ah I can only advise is ah
You should have the right mindset and
The right attitude to begin with and
like what Uh What Jess said earlier
ah Accept the flaw and work on it so
you know you can achieve what
you want and It's okay to be insecure as long
as you do something about
and Of course we know ah  frankly
speaking the first reaction really of
everything  especially Uh of the opposite
sex is physical what you see
so work on that if you really want to
meet and Uh you know be with the girl of
your dreams and I guess I would add
Al because He said once you
feel healthy once you feel comfortable
and confident it will exude and
hopefully that will attract the girl of
your dreams Isn't it like you There it is
Oh
hi Grabe onong duaan Kinikilik ako nakaikilik
Kayo Kinikilik ako galag ganun ng
ganon eh doc J may kagat pa yun Saab
Oh you wish me a pwede I know I'm not the one
you asked But rooted on that
question you had for Alden that's why
self love is so important because if
you don't love yourself you will love
other people How do you love
other people right completely agree Okay
for you how how the question is
Yes I am joining a beauty pageant how to
lose 10 lbs in one month
specific wow Grabe I haven't been able to lose
10 lbs in one month
um maybe let's What Let's let's  be
realistic about your goals um of course
there is training for that ' is
joining a beauty pagent um I think it is
a bit unhealthy to lose 10
pounds in a month so I think it is more
important
to be more regular Your progress I
mean it is more gradual more slowly
But somehow sure After
your beauty pageant you will be like that I guess it is
not just because of the beauty pageant and
because of the pressure that is why you lost 10
PBS So it really doesn't matter because
Sometimes  I mean I'm not a I'm not
a professional trainer or or a
nutritionist but um when you are
you are already exposed to fitness and then
to information like
muscle is heavier than fat um you
also need to accept that it's not all about the
weight It's about how you look and
sometimes you know the weight is crazy
I mean The weighing scale When
you see it Yes the numbers When
you see your weight seems
heavy but your appearance Okay I
think you have to base on that and of
course what's important there You have to
be you know at your best Um
your health should be at its best because of
course when you enter a beauty
pageant or a competition
your mind should also be alert ' ba So that's hard when you
diet you crush diet all
just all Just in one month it's hard
so you know my advice to you is just be
healthy just do the best what you could
do and good luck with your p this is just a follow up
Fast for SAO ha fast fast just
Um what was or what  is your
biggest body
insecurity my biggest body insecurity
would be my arms Because what eh um
my arms are really big ah I thought maybe
others thought no I'll answer size
because I was bashed before because of my
thighs but my biggest insecurity is my
arms because um you know know we
all know this when you're on TV you gain 10
lbs and especially I'm so white
when the light bounces off me I
get bigger so my biggest insecurity is that
but I've learned to accept it and
somehow it became this because of
my cocoa workout but that's ah that's all
but the important thing is that um let
me Just you know repeat What alin said
earlier is you do something about so
thank you very much for EA Okay yes
hello miss isa How are you after your
health problems 2020 What are the things
you have done After you recovered has
the virus changed
you Thank you
um it has it has changed me but not
physically it changed me mentally Uh it
like I said earlier um there are a lot
of realizations that Reflection points
that that I had because of covid-19
that made me value my life more my
health and of course the people around
me so i think that is really the biggest
change it It's somehow an awakening um
ah It's like It made me humble and realize
that I'm not Invincible it's
like I have to respect my body It made
me Humble in recognizing How important
other people are in my life and um
mother nature as well because we do live
in this home wwf Luis Yeah hi Panda Hi
Panda and then um Yeah It made me  value
time and that's that's the change that
Uh it gave me so there was an awakening
And I You know how easy it is to forget But
this is something there Luis
No buse we're still here we still remember
it It's It will be a constant
reminder to myself of what it was that I
had to learn and I learned during that
time because we can quickly forget about
these things and I I hope that I don't
so let's remember the lessons that life
has taught us buse  They're very
important Yeah than Okay Alden  for SAO
naman to Would you consider yourself
financially and emotionally ready if
ever You get married right now w w
boom
ah the answer is Yes
wow ready Okay I'll continue that I'll
continue let's leave it there
of course let's give a bit of privacy
Alden so Alden so Luis you're ready
oh oh
my my let's leave it door son
of tinola an ak cheers yes let's just say
if we use what
a Game Show game said
that was a
hit Or a game like that is easy for
me The Next question is for you
Hello doctor can men get lumps in
breasts can men get breast cancer how
likely Yes males can get breast cancer
Uh Although It's rare But it doesn't
exempt them to do a self breast exam and
to be more conscious in terms of
physical health Thank you very much doc
this is another question to lis you're so handsome
I think you're perfect I think you've never
eaten chili my mommy is sorry sorry
my mommy is I love youy
ganon how how this is for you again how do
you stay motivated to work out  Oh my
gosh it's hard because you know me right?
I want to be honest about this. I'm not
always motivated to work out. That's why
I said earlier, "It's PR. I'm
pressured to be fit for life." I
guess what? It's more important that
you know your goals and you
set a goal for yourself. You
shouldn't have a deadline. I mean, it's
good that you have a deadline. You have to prepare for something.
But it's more like,
you have to think of it as a life.
Like, for everything. The
motivation comes from you. Of
course, your partner or your friends.
Or of course, yourself too. But not
all of us are always motivated. So that's
one thing you should remember. Of
course, set a goal for yourself.
Look for workouts or people who
inspire you. That's also how
you stay motivated. And just where you're at your best and
where you're happiest,
I feel like you're more down, you're more down. Shift
your focus to being motivated. To
motivate yourself.  I'll just share what
I'm doing, think of it as a joke,
not a joke. I'm serious, I'm going to say something really neat.
You'll laugh right away. I follow the 33 rule. The
33 rule is I rest after 3 days of
working out and I don't go past 3 days
of
resting for me. It's okay to rest for 3 days,
then you work out. As long as you don't
go past 3. As long as you don't go past 3 days after days of working
out. I must take a rest day to recover,
especially when you're doing something intense. And
don't go past three rest days so that at
least you don't lose the momentum. It's okay to rest.
That's how your body recovers. That's how your muscles grow
through rest. Isn't it supposed to be? I'm
sorry. Oh, it should be. I thought about it too.
Sorry. I just want to add this. Um,
maybe it shouldn't be. Because sometimes when
we work out, everyone
here knows. You feel like you're under pressure.
I think about it too. Because sometimes
people ask
how to motivate yourself. You.
shouldn't think of working out as you
know as a punishment so Dapat sakto
yyung balanse of resting and also of you
know of pushing yourself because sometimes you
lose motivation when you're too much
pushing yourself and
instead of you know um working towards
that goal suddenly you just get
stressed so it's part of What's that too
'ba of of mentally prepared na dapat
hindi punishment yung pagwo-workout for
you meron na pwede ako pwede ako mag-add
Yes um also I hope we get into this
mindset trend that we exercise to be
fit L that will happen eventually but the
fitness part being physically
healthy I think that's Dapat maging
goal natin and the rest will follow because
Jess is right you can get pressured into
it
ah but the fit is really I have been
there done that eh so ah I
ignored him too much So that's a May
message d J The question is for you and
this is very timely if you're on Social
Media you know this is a timely issue
now do you believe alternative medicines
can cure cancer because many people say
that  you know your Typical cancer
treatment would be very very expensive
so some people would Resort to
alternative medicine What do you think
Uh let's Stick to the evidence-based Uh
treatment which which is chemotherapy
radiation or there are hormonal Uh
medications for that that is still the gold
standard and i'll Stick to that is G
question Yes Go ahead but that's but i
but if we incorporate Uh integrative
medicine with western science-based ones
that that can also work Cor yes yes that
can that can or they go hand in hand Yes
one  last question because I do know you
have a very busy Day.
It's okay.
How do you make self love possible
with all the you know failures and heavy
pressure that life throws at us. I think
that's what I answered earlier um you
know like um life I gave it earlier and I
hope you still remember it but
um again I will go back to this very
simple answer that I learned This this
um phrase was Uh said during a
mental health webinar that doc G and I
were part of um despite all the heavy
pressures in life  and there will be no
matter who you are No Matter Where You
come From what you do there are
challenges in life now I think that
it is so vital for us to be able to
recognize how we can turn that struggle
into our strength Yeah nice yeah and
that being said do you have any final
words for our viewers right now before
we end our
session I'm really Okay um yeah I
think um right now I I just want to say
thank you I would like to honor each and
every participant here who shared their
story um and Uh I'm honored to be part
of this webinar I would  like to thank
manu life for having me and to everyone
watching now I hope that you have
learned something from our
conversation and
um life is truly precious life can be
beautiful I think it's It's a matter of
us trying to find the beauty in each and
every moment not just in the grand um
moments of life it can be found in these
interactions that we have um and so
let's check Cherish it let's value it
because we only have one life so Thank
you very much thank you very much  one how
how Wow it seems I really agree with
everything  that youve said isa um Yun nga
Um thank you Thank you so much manu
life for having me here and of course sa
lahat ng nandogon ngayon um it's
actually my first webinar so thank you
so much for the opportunity I'm so happ
last I hope so Um thank you so much for
the opportunity for giving me a chance to
share Uh my story and my journey with
everyone here um isas right life is very
important and you know um tuod ng sabi
niya kanina Mahirap kapag pagalai tayong
puro trabaho tapos We don't see or we
don't take care of you know kung para
saan nga ba talaga yung ginawa natin
So I think lagi k sinabihan holistic
lahan kahit pa mapa mapa healthwise
mapay even with your loved ones It's so
important to take care of yourself to be able to take care of
the people that you
love so sana lahat tayo dito Maraming untuk menjadi I'm For
sure ako Maraming untuk menjadi
so thank you everyone also isa
Dr g d g alen of course for sharing your
Journey with me to so thank you Thank
you man for having me today
um Syempre Uh first and foremost I would
like to thank man for  coming up to this
webinar I think because
we need it now especially our topic
right now being healthy and Uh you know
taking care of ourselves first because
of What's happening around us and of
course Uh Uh I'm very honored to be here
with this Uh beautiful beautiful and
inspirational speakers
I also learned a lot listening ah while on
standby Thank you very much for all the
knowledge You've given to us and of
course to our participants here Of course it's
from brother Luis that I
made you
laugh and
contributed I'm very honored And I hope
that you've learned something Uh From Us
Uh our little story Our Little
inspirational story and I hope that
you'll be able to get something right after this webinar to be a
better person thank you thank you very
much brother DC J ah thanks again to
manel for this chance sobrang dream ko
lang makasama Ong nasa panel and for
making it come through and again I'll
just end on this note that Hwag tayong manali
ng pag-asa that all this will be
over so mahirap Iyung Journey but let's
all anchor din sa hope na matatapos din
so once  again thank you very much d
Gia isa Jess and Alden for sharing your
own journeys to good health and wellness
It is a wonderful experience having trev
stage with these inspiring individuals
once again Many many thanks and
stay safe Thank you thank you thank
you thank you very much now everyone
please stay for the raffle at the end of
this program You know the many
insights gained from this webinar and
I Hope it's the same for all our viewers
our guest speakers Enlighten us on how
important it is to be  prepared to face
uncertainties and how we can all have a
personalized Journey towards health and
and fitness Canaman manual life
Philippines has this very special treat
for all of us manual life health flex
the first and only fully customizable
health insurance plan that's affordable
and is available until age 70 so before
we announce our raffle winners watch
this very short video to find out How
you can enjoy a health plan that's made
perfectly for
[Music]
you being young doesn't mean you can't
worry  about getting sick that's why i
make sure that  I Stay active everyday to
keep me fit and healthy but that's not
enough you also need to protect yourself
from life's curve balls now more than
ever you need a health plan that fits
you better manu life's newest health
insurance plan health flex is the first
customizable health insurance plan that
has four
bundles Do you know that according to
manual recent health study survey cancer
is the most feared illness among
Filipinos if heal cancer worry less for
about 1,000 a Month this plan gives you
300,000 worth of coverage with other
cancer related treatment benefits This
Is a Smart investment for young working
professionals like me health a 3 c
bundle covers not just cancer but also
heart attack and sh and these are the
top three most common critical illnesses
among Filipinos get this spleen now for
just a little over 1,000 per
month our third bundle helpx cancer plus
is a comprehensive plan that provides
coverage for cancer and 57 other
advanced critical illnesses these
include male cancer early stage  critical
illness child critical illness and
recovery benefits  this gives someone
like me who's just starting out of
family the confidence and peace of mind
that my loved ones and I are truly
protected for as low as 1,300 per month
and the fourth bundle health flex 3 c
plus gives coverage from top three
critical illnesses and feel more Secure
with protection from up to
112 critical illnesses All These for
just
1,600 a month manual life health flex is
the health insurance plan that let you
choose and pay only for the coverage  you
need for a health plan that fits you
perfectly choose manual health talk to
your financial advisor today
[Music]
w Absolutely there is a perfect for you
man life to choose What fits your health
plan right new product offering he now
this pandemic has certainly heeded our
awareness about our health now we hope
This webinar help you realize now more
than ever you need a health protects you
from life's uncertainties we all know
preparation is key make your health your
top priority if you have an existing
financial  advisor and would like to know
more about this New affordable  and
customizable Health product Please do
Schedule a call and of course expect a
message from your financial advisor
right after this webinar So for those
without a financial advisor you may
reach out to us via the contact details
on your
screens now I hope everyone feels
renewed and empowered as Although
I know you are a little bit of us because of course
we already know that We have something
special for all our viewers It is time
to show our winners for this afternoon's
webinar raffle so congratulations to the
raffle winners that are now flashed  on
the
screen Congratulations Joann Lin
u and congratulations to eileen gladis
here
[Music]
Thank you very much and enjoy But before
we end this webinar we would like to get
your feedback on this comment for us to
continue delivering helpful webinars in
the months to come So please answer our
short survey by scanning the QR code
that will be flashed on screen there you
go that's it and that wraps up this
afternoon's wellness webinar this has
been your host luis manzano I am leaving
this webinar with a renewed mindset to
keep pushing for a healthier life I hope
this web  starts your Journey or
continues your progress in making your
day everyday better Thank you and
stay safe everyone take care
[Music]
ready
lif you need a health plan that fits you
better get manual life health
flex choose from four health bundles to
get coverage for cancer heart attack
stroke and over 100 other critical
[Music]
illnesses so you can start to make every
day
better find healthy that fits you
perfectly ask your insurance advisor
about it
ready
lif you need a health plan that fits you
better get manual life health
flex choose from four health bundles to
get coverage for cancer heart attack
stroke and over 100 other critical
illnesses so you can start to make every
day
better find healthy that fits you
perfectly ask your insurance advisor
about it
ready
lif you need a health plan that fits you
better get manual life health
flex choose from four health bundles to
get coverage for cancer heart attack
stroke and over 100 other critical
illnesses so you can start to make every
day
better find healthy that fits you
perfectly ask your insurance advisor
about l
[Applause]
[Music]
b
[Applause]
[Music]
life what
diverse and now more ever
unpredictable aidc of moments moments
shaped by the decisions we make and all
of us make thousands every single day
these decisions can be comp from how we
choose to invest to for later Life To
Reaching our greatest goals we make
these decisions easier every so everyone
can live
better every better  this drives what we
do from sharing investment insights that
Others may not see to helping her make
sure his education is covered from
rewarding him for staying healthy to
giving her the confidence to
S every day better is doing a job that
improves people lives and Believing That
tomrow be better than to
evening challenging mons by deciding to
to and
important
smiling
every let Mak every
[Music]
better
ready l